

Kirkland, WA

✓ dale@riechert.me

 https://dale.riechert.me/ https://linkedin.com/in/daleriechert

Highly adaptable software engineer with over 8 years experience touching upon all stages of the software life cycle. Proven in growing and leading testing and solutions teams. Also proficient and passionate toward UX design, code development, DevOps, technical support, data analytics, and artificial intelligence at innovative technology companies.

experience

Marriott International | Bethesda, MA (Remote) Senior Software Engineer | May 2024 - Present

- Developing backend software in TypeScript with Node.js in close conjunction with neighboring teams to transition legacy communication systems serving millions of customers to a modern platform utilizing AWS, Kafka, Confluent, and Kubernetes
- Expanded environment observability for support teams through improved logging with Winston and ingested into dashboards in Dynatrace

⊗ Esper | Bellevue, WA

Senior Solutions Engineer | Feb. 2022 - Sep. 2023

- Worked closely with sales team and stakeholders arranging technical solutions to guide five to six-figure business opportunities for Esper MDM and Foundation OS SaaS products
- Coordinated with product management and development through triaging and addressing all ticketed customer concerns from across the entire solutions team each week
- Streamlined technical presales cycle in Salesforce with new processes and documentation to shorten time to close

Presales/Solutions Engineer | Jan. 2021 - Feb. 2022

- Guided customers and sales daily through face-to-face communication, email, and expanded documentation
- Developed Python scripts and tools using Esper's APIs to crucially extend functionality of the product
- Flashed, troubleshooted, and analyzed dozens of unique Android devices to grow known product support base
- Established internal systems to track incoming new customers and support efforts

Microsoft | Redmond, WA

Lead Test Engineer | Apr. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Lead the creation of all binaries, testing, and releases on daily and weekly routines for Skype and Teams for Home
- Coordinated with product management and development each week on blocking issues and ensuring test coverage as features were added or removed
- Rebuilt all test documentation and data analysis reports ground up utilizing Azure DevOps, SharePoint, and Power BI
- Owned the CI/CD and test automation pipelines in Azure DevOps to maintain and improve coverage and efficiencies

Test Engineer | Mar. 2017 - Apr. 2019

- Conducted daily comprehensive testing of Skype and created actionable reports of all discovered issues
- Trained and lead new team members as testing efforts quadrupled in size to over twelve people
- Developed reliable and efficient test automation with Selenium and Appium in Python on 11 different platforms

education

Arizona State University | Tempe, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Informatics | Aug. 2010 - May 2016

- App development using Java, C++, HTML/CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and REST APIs
- Database design using Microsoft Access, XML, and SQL
- UI/UX research, design, user testing, and evaluation using paper, Axure, and Justinmind prototypes
- Media editing using Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, 3ds Max, and Rhinoceros
- Game design and development in GameMaker and Unity
- Multimedia system building and programming using Arduino (C/C++), Max, and Processing

knowledge & skills

Software and Libraries

- Windows, MacOS, Linux, Android/AOSP, iOS
- Git, GitHub, Visual Studio, Postman, Jira, Confluence, Salesforce, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Office Suite, Power BI, SharePoint, Selenium, Appium, Android Studio, Dynatrace, Adobe Creative Suite

Development Languages

- C, C++, Java, Python, JavaScript/TypeScript, PHP
- HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, XPath, Regex, SQL, REST APIs